Guide to the Elizabeth Page Harris Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
The more formal involvement of Elizabeth Page with the Quaker movement is found in the subsection for Society of Friends. It consists of correspondence, minutes of meetings, newsletters, publications, and reports concerning Quaker meetings, Friends lobbying efforts, Quaker education, and the activities of other Quaker organizations. The Orange Grove Monthly Meeting files, particularly the correspondence, provide the most complete information on Bee's early involvement in the Society of Friends. Correspondents include Hugh Anderson, Elsie Dorland, George F. Howell, clerk of the meeting, Susan A. Howell, and Patrick Lloyd.
Material on the evacuation and relocation of California Japanese Americans in World War II is found in the Japanese Relocation subsection (Boxes 79-82). Elizabeth Page, a member of both the Pasadena Committee for Fair Play and the Interracial Relations Committee of the Pacific Coast Branch of the AFSC, opposed this panicky response to Pearl Harbor and through correspondence and acts of kindness sought to alleviate the plight of the Nisei. Important Japanese American correspondents between 1942-1945 included Nobu T. Kawai, president of the Pasadena Chapter of the Japanese Americans Citizens League, and such ordinary people as Yoneko Hashimoto, Yumiji Higashi, Akiko Taketa, Mary Uemoto, and Ruth Watanabe. The subsection also contains an interesting selection of Nisei newsletters and newspapers, the most important being the Gila News-Courier published in Rivers, Arizona; Heart Mountain Sentinel from Heart Mountain, Wyoming; Pacific Citizen published in Salt Lake City, Utah; The Poston "Press Bulletin" from Poston, Arizona; and the Tulare News from Tulare, California.
The final subsection, Other Causes, contains papers of additional pacifist and internationalist organizations. Among the many such organizations were the American Civil Liberties Union, the Commission to Study the Organization of Peace, Federal Union Inc., the Fellowship of Reconciliation, National Service Board for Religious Objectors, the Socialist Party, and the United States Committee for the Care of European Children. Bee was a founding member of the Fellowship of Reconciliation, a member in long standing of the Socialist Party, and belonged to several conscientious onjector organizations. The largest quantity of material concerns the Federal Union, Inc., movement (Boxes 83-84, folders 1819-1844). Originally called Inter-Democracy Federal Unionists, the organization was established to promote the internationalist ideals of Clarence K. Streit, author of Union Now; A Proposal for a Federal Union of the Democracies of the North Atlantic. Elizabeth Page became a member of the Council of Advisors of Federal Union, Inc. in December, 1939 and lectured on behalf of the organization in 1940. In January 1941, however, she resigned from the Advisory Board because she believed that it had become an organization devoted to entering the war on the side of Great Britain. Prominent Federal Unionist correspondents are Rita Carlin, Gordon Mannerstedt, Vernon Nash, Lee Shippey, Clarence K. Streit, and Anne Walters.
The writings of Elizabeth Page, both published and unpublished, are contained in Series V, Boxes 87-108. Alphabetically arranged book length manuscripts take up more than twenty boxes. The final box and one-half in the series consists of two book reviews and drafts of short stories and other writings.
Elizabeth Page's earliest writings are located in Family Papers. See Box 32, folders 769-775 and Box 53, folders 1155-1156. Her first serious writings date from the 1914-1915 era and consist of a Colombia University M.A. thesis, "Immigration to the American Colonies Between 1690-1765"; a semiautobiographical account of a trip to the West Coast written by Elizabeth Page and Caroline Marsh Roe, "The Trail of the Grafters"; and a draft of In Camp and Tepee. This latter work was published in 1915 and Bee's mother was listed as its author, although in the preface Bee is virtually given joint author credit. Copies of In Camp and Tepee are found in the Page Family Papers (Box 12, folder 231).
Wagons West (1930), Elizabeth Page's first published book, was closely followed by Wild Horses and Gold (1932). For these and later works, the material is arranged in the following order. First comes an outline or synopsis; followed by chronologically arranged drafts of manuscripts, and then by such things as notes, publicity, and reviews. As one might expect, The Tree of Liberty (1939) takes up the most space in Series V. Included are three drafts and a portion of a fourth earlier one; a copy of the Literary Guild version of the book and four foreign language editions; announcements, best seller lists, and publicity; and an extensive file of American and British reviews. Some enthusiastic reviewers characterized The Tree of Liberty as the great American novel. The front page review in The New York Times Book Review of February 26, 1939 was written by the eminent historian, Henry Steele Commager, and the book was on the best seller list for most of the year. Scripts, programs, publicity, reviews, and other papers for "The Howards of Virginia" are also included. After the sale of movie rights to The Tree of Liberty, Elizabeth Page served as a script writer for two movies, "The Dark Command" and "Dawn's Early Light". "The Dark Command" was released in 1940, but "Dawn's Early Light", a historical drama on the life of Alexander Hamilton which featured such memorable lines as, "After you're dead, who's going to remember what's in The Federalist", was never filmed. The series also contains manuscripts and other papers of Heritage and Challenge, Elizabeth Page's unpublished life of Thomas Jefferson.
Writings concludes with two 1934 book reviews and manuscript drafts of short stories and other writings. It appears that only one short story, "Reversed Revenge" (Box 107, folders 2211-2213), was ever published.
Series VI, Printed Works, contains alphabetically arranged Books (Boxes 109-112, folders 2223-2244) and Shorter Works (Boxes 112-116, folders 2250-2330). Most belonged to Elizabeth Page Harris, but some came from the library of Theodora Kellogg. The series includes a copy of Burton Harris' John Colter: His Years in the Rockies (1952).
The final series, Photographs, is divided into four alphabetically arranged parts: People, Places, Albums, and Oversize. Three photo albums and eleven folders of photographs belonged to Theodora Kellogg. Following the Oversize material is a folio of photographs, diplomas, pages of newspapers, and other papers.
Box 128 houses an Addition to the Elizabeth Page Harris Papers. It primarily contains postcards, but also includes some letters of Elizabeth Page Harris and Herbert Taylor Harris from the 1950's.
Biographical / Historical
Elizabeth Merwin Page Harris, author, graduated from Vassar College (1912) and received an M.A. from Columbia University (1914). She was a teacher (1914-1916), Y.M.C.A. worker during World War I, and an International Grenfell Association volunteer (1921-1925) and secretary (1927-1931). Elizabeth Page wrote four books, including the 1939 best seller, The Tree of Liberty.
Elizabeth Page sold the film rights for The Tree of Liberty to Columbia Pictures in 1939 for $55,000. The resulting movie, starring Cary Grant and Martha Scott, was called "The Howards of Virginia" (1940). A final book, Wilderness Adventure, which the author characterized as a "penny dreadful", was published in 1946. For most of the last thirty years of her life, Elizabeth Page devoted her writing energies to a monumental two volume life of Thomas Jefferson titled Heritage and Challenge. The first volume of this labor of love concerned Jefferson's Virginia between the years 1612-1739 and the second volume covered his life to 1766. The work suffered from what one editor considered "iffiness" and what others called conjecture and creative fiction. Occupying a neverland between scholarly biography and historical fiction, the manuscript was rejected by commercial publishers and university presses.
During World War II, Elizabeth Page became active in Quaker and pacifist causes. She was a member of the Orange Grove Monthly Meeting in Pasadena, California, was concerned with the refugee work of the American Friends Service Committee, and served in the Philadelphia office of the Committee at the International Centers Subcommittee, Foreign Service Section 1945-1947. In 1940 she was on the Council of Advisors and served as lecturer for Federal Union, Inc., originally called Inter-Democracy Federal Unionists.
After her mother's death in Sierra Madre, California in September 1943, she moved to the family home in Manchester, Vermont, where she resided for much of the rest of her life. She married Dr. Herbert Taylor Harris (1879-1960) of Basin, Wyoming in December 1954 and died on March 11, 1969 in Oaxaca, Mexico of "lymphatic leukemia" from which she had suffered for fifteen years.
Additional biographical information can be found in Series II of the Elizabeth Page Harris Papers (Box 30, folders 719-31).
Society of Friends; Conscientious objectors; Families; Japanese Americans -- Evacuation and relocation, 1942-1945; Pacifism; Single women; World War, 1914-1918 -- War work -- Young Men's Christian Associations; World War, 1939-1945 -- Refugees; Basin (Wyo.); Newfoundland and Labrador -- Economic conditions; White Bay (N.L.); Juvenilia; Photoprints; Pacifists; Women authors; Allardyce, Elsie G., Lady; Burton, Anna Robertson, d. 1948; Cleghorn, Sarah Norcliffe, 1876-1959; Crook, Mary S., 1865-; DuPuis, Grace Evangeline Bear, d. 1951; Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1879-1958; Grenfell, Anne, 1885-1938; Grenfell, Wilfred Thomason, Sir, 1865-1940; Harris, Elizabeth Merwin Page, 1889-1969; Kellogg, Theodora, 1887-1948; Lyman, Elizabeth Dudley Schauffler, 1925-; Page, Angeline Rider, 1840-1918; Page, Elizabeth, 1889-; Pearson, Edith K., 1872-; Schauffler, Caroline Brown, 1914-; Schauffler, Marjorie Page, 1897-1983; Schauffler, Richard Manvel, 1921-; Smith, Bradford, 1909-1964; Streit, Clarence K. (Clarence Kirshman), 1896-1986; Vannier, Marion Lydia, 1877-1966; Vruwink, Henry Andrew, 1886-; Wickwire, Byron F., 1863-1943; Burton family; Harris family; Page family; Rowe family; Schauffler family; American Friends Service Committee; Federal Union, Inc. (Washington, D.C.); International Grenfell Association; Vassar College. Class of 1912
- Correspondence, 1895-1973; Series I; 11.75' (28 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, CORRESPONDENCE, fills Boxes 1 - 28 of the Elizabeth Page Harris Papers. The correspondence is chronologically arranged. Undated correspondence is located in Boxes 27-28, folders 671-679. Christmas cards and other greeting cards are placed last in Box 28 and are chronologically arranged.
  - 1895 - 1916 September (Box 1, Folder 1-26)
  - 1916 October - 1921 June (Box 2, Folder 27-49)
  - 1921 July - 1930 October (Box 3, Folder 50-78)
  - 1930 November - 1934 April (Box 4, Folder 79-107)
  - 1934 May - 1938 October (Box 5, Folder 108-134)
  - 1938 November - 1939 June (Box 6, Folder 135-156)
  - 1939 June - 1940 April (Box 7, Folder 157-178)
  - 1940 April - 1941 May (Box 8, Folder 179-204)
  - 1941 June - 1942 March (Box 9, Folder 205-226)
  - 1942 April - 1943 January (Box 10, Folder 227-249)
  - 1943 February - 1943 September (Box 11, Folder 250-272)
  - 1943 October - 1944 April (Box 12, Folder 273-294)
  - 1944 May - 1945 February (Box 13, Folder 295-316)
  - 1945 March - 1946 March (Box 14, Folder 317-339)
  - 1946 March - 1948 July (Box 15, Folder 340-364)
  - 1948 July - 1949 April (Box 16, Folder 365-387)
  - 1949 May - 1950 February (Box 17, Folder 388-410)
  - 1950 February - 1951 February (Box 18, Folder 411-433)
  - 1951 March - 1952 August (Box 19, Folder 434-457)
  - 1952 September - 1954 May (Box 20, Folder 458-481)
  - 1954 June - 1955 (Box 21, Folder 482-503)
  - 1956 January - 1958 February (Box 22, Folder 504-530)
  - 1958 February - 1960 May (Box 23, Folder 531-559)
  - 1960 June - 1962 August (Box 24, Folder 560-585)
  - 1962 September - 1964 (Box 25, Folder 586-615)
  - 1965 January - 1967 June (Box 26, Folder 616-644)
  - 1967 July - 1973 (Box 27, Folder 645-670)
  - Harris, Elizabeth Merwin Page, undated (Box 27, Folder 671)
  - Harris, Herbert Burton, undated (Box 27, Folder 672)
  - Harris, Lorle Kempe (Box 27, Folder 672)
  - Merritt, Edith A., undated (Box 27, Folder 673)
  - Schauffler, Marjorie Page, undated (Box 27, Folder 674)
  - Stirling, Dorothy, undated (Box 27, Folder 675)
  - A-V, undated (Box 28, Folder 676-678)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 28, Folder 679)
  - Letter fragments, undated (Box 28, Folder 680)
  - Christmas cards, 1910-1966, undated (Box 28, Folder 681-692)
  - Christmas cards with pictures of friends, undated (Box 28, Folder 693)
  - Greeting cards, 1952-1966, undated (Box 28, Folder 694-697)
- Family Papers, 1808-1978; Series II; 12.5' (28 boxes)
  Series II, FAMILY PAPERS, is found in Boxes 29-56 of the Elizabeth Page Harris Papers. The material is arranged alphabetically by person or subject and then chronologically.
  - Addresses, 1908-1968, undated (Box 29, Folder 698-703)
  - Announcements and invitations, 1908-1964, undated (Box 29, Folder 704)
  - Art work
    - Drawing, undated (Box 29, Folder 705)
    - Sketch of cowboy, undated (Box 29, Folder 706)
    - Sketch of squirrel, undated (Box 29, Folder 707)
    - Water color of church, undated (Box 29, Folder 708)
    - Water color of unidentified female, undated (Box 29, Folder 709)
  - Autograph book, 1966 (Box 29, Folder 710)
  - Basin, Wyoming, 1944-1958 (Box 29, Folder 711)
    - St. Andrew's Episcopal Church, 1958-1968, undated (Box 29, Folder 712)
  - Bills and receipts, 1922-1966 (Box 29, Folder 713-717)
  - Bills and receipts, 1965-1966 (Box 30, Folder 718)
  - Biographical
    General
    See also: box 127A
    - Biographical notes, 1974, undated (Box 30, Folder 720)
    - Death, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 721)
    - Death instructions, 1950-1963 (Box 30, Folder 722)
    - Donations in memory of, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 723)
    - Locks of hair, 1893, undated (Box 30, Folder 724)
    - Marriage announcement, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 725)
    - Marriage service, 1954 (Box 30, Folder 726)
    - Medical information, 1938-1969, undated (Box 30, Folder 727)
    - Obituaries, 1969 (Box 30, Folder 728)
    - "Patchwork Quilt" by Elizabeth Dudley Schauffler Lyman, 1975 (Box 30, Folder 729)
    - Statement, undated (Box 30, Folder 730)
    - Wills, 1939-1960 (Box 30, Folder 731)
  - Book list, 1944 (Box 30, Folder 732)
  - Bookplates, miscellaneous, undated (Box 30, Folder 733)
  - Burns, Elinor Prudden, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 734)
  - Burton family, undated (Box 30, Folder 735)
  - Business cards, undated (Box 30, Folder 736)
  - Camp Fire Girls, 1922-1923 (Box 30, Folder 737)
  - The Canadian Guild of Health, 1927, 1931, undated (Box 30, Folder 741)
  - Card plate, undated (Box 30, Folder 742)
  - The Carlinville Democrat, 1930 (Box 30, Folder 743)
  - Charitable contributions, 1921-1968 (Box 30, Folder 744)
  - Childhood years
    - "Bomoseen Ballads", undated (Box 30, Folder 745)
    - Drawing of Map of Italy, undated (Box 30, Folder 746)
    - Eighth grade examination, undated (Box 30, Folder 747)
    - Excellence in deportment, 1898-1901 (Box 30, Folder 748)
    - Exercises, undated (Box 31, Folder 749)
    - Grammar school notebook, undated (Box 31, Folder 750)
    - Junior Christian Endeavor, undated (Box 31, Folder 751)
    - Miscellaneous., undated (Box 31, Folder 752-753)
    - School work
      - Algebra exam, 1908 (Box 31, Folder 754)
      - Compositions, 1899-1902, undated (Box 31, Folder 755-756)
      - Notebook on ancient history, undated (Box 31, Folder 757)
      - Notebook on critical reading, undated (Box 31, Folder 758)
      - Notebook of maps on English, history, undated (Box 31, Folder 759)
      - Notebook on French history, undated (Box 31, Folder 760)
      - Notebooks on history and literature, undated (Box 31, Folder 761)
      - Notebook on literature, undated (Box 31, Folder 762)
      - Notebook on Roman history, undated (Box 32, Folder 763)
      - Notes on Algebra, undated (Box 32, Folder 764)
      - Notes on botany and geometry, undated (Box 32, Folder 765)
    - Sketches, 1904, undated (Box 32, Folder 766)
    - Steamer letter, undated (Box 32, Folder 767)
    - Valentine book, undated (Box 32, Folder 768)
    - Writings, 1902, 1906, undated (Box 32, Folder 769-771)
      - "A Fisherman of Iceland," translated by Elizabeth M. Page, 1908 (Box 32, Folder 772)
      - "The Highty-Tighty Tales", undated (Box 32, Folder 773)
      - "Puss in Boots", undated (Box 32, Folder 774)
      - "The Romance of Castle Rosario", undated (Box 32, Folder 775)
  - Christmas lists, 1924-1954, undated (Box 32, Folder 776)
  - Cleghorn, Sarah N.: "Ballad of Gene Debs", 1928 (Box 32, Folder 777)
  - Clubs, undated (Box 32, Folder 778)
  - Columbia University, 1913-1914 (Box 32, Folder 779)
    - Notes on American history, 1850-1865, 1913 (Box 32, Folder 780)
    - Notes on Colonial American history, 1913-1914 (Box 32, Folder 781)
    - Notes on the history of modern Europe, 1914 (Box 33, Folder 782)
    - Notes on the history of Western Europe, undated (Box 33, Folder 783)
    - Notes on the social and industrial history of England, undated (Box 33, Folder 784)
  - Consumer cooperatives, 1936-1943, undated (Box 33, Folder 785)
  - Credit cards, 1942-1943 (Box 33, Folder 786)
  - Deeds, 1931-1946 (Box 33, Folder 787)
  - De Vaughn, Amelia, 1944-1946 (Box 33, Folder 788)
  - Diary notes and writings, 1905, undated (Box 33, Folder 789)
  - Diaries, 1906-1944 (Box 33, Folder 790-793)
    See also: Box 108, folder 2202
  - Diaries, 1945-1968 (Box 34, Folder 794-800)
  - Directions, undated (Box 34, Folder 801)
  - Estate
    - Bailey inquiry, 1971 (Box 34, Folder 802)
    - Expenses, 1969-1971 (Box 34, Folder 803-804)
    - Funeral expenses, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 805)
    - Gifts and contributions, 1969-1972, undated (Box 34, Folder 806)
    - Income taxes, 1969-1970 (Box 34, Folder 807)
    - Inventories, 1970-1971 (Box 34, Folder 808)
    - Meacham, Sidney J., 1969-1972 (Box 34, Folder 809-811)
    - Papers, 1969-1971, undated (Box 34, Folder 812)
    - Pond, Louise A., 1972 (Box 34, Folder 813)
  - Expenses, 1937-1951, undated (Box 34, Folder 814)
    - Automobile, 1941 (Box 34, Folder 815)
    - Moving, 1941-1967 (Box 34, Folder 816)
    - Notebook, undated (Box 34, Folder 817)
  - Fan lists, undated (Box 34, Folder 818)
  - Finances
    - Bank books, 1916-1926 (Box 34, Folder 819)
    - Bank books, 1932-1958 (Box 35, Folder 820)
    - Bank records, 1920-1964, undated (Box 35, Folder 821-824)
    - Charitable contributions and interest, 1934-1938 (Box 35, Folder 825)
    - Debts and loans, 1933-1961, undated (Box 35, Folder 826-827)
    - Elizabeth P. Harris Trust
      - Accounting, 1963-1971 (Box 35, Folder 828-832)
      - Correspondence, 1963-1978 (Box 35, Folder 833-836)
      - Income tax, 1964 (Box 35, Folder 837)
      - Investment analysis, 1963-1971 (Box 35, Folder 838-839)
      - Trust agreement, 1963-1966 (Box 35, Folder 840)
    - Employer unemployment compensation, 1959-1966 (Box 35, Folder 841)
    - Employer's taxes, 1939-1970 (Box 35, Folder 842-843)
    - Expenses, undated (Box 35, Folder 844)
      - Cash journals, 1934-1943 (Box 36, Folder 845-847)
      - Cash journal, 1935-1956 (Box 37, Folder 848)
      - Cash journal, 1944-1948 (Box 38, Folder 849)
      - Cash journal, 1951-1956 (Box 39, Folder 850)
    - Financial reports, 1947-1948 (Box 40, Folder 851)
    - Income taxes, 1939-1967 (Box 40, Folder 852-854)
    - Investment information, 1929-1954, undated (Box 40, Folder 855)
    - Investment record, 1955-1962 (Box 40, Folder 856)
    - Investments, 1928-1963, undated (Box 40, Folder 857-860)
    - Joseph Wickham Roe Trust, 1964-1966 (Box 40, Folder 861)
    - Miscellaneous, 1963-1968 (Box 40, Folder 862)
    - Monthly income, undated (Box 40, Folder 863)
    - Social Security records, 1957-1967 (Box 40, Folder 864-865)
    - Vassar annuities, 1938 (Box 40, Folder 866)
  - Fisher, Dorothy Canfield, 1930-1959 (Box 40, Folder 867)
  - Form letters, 1939 (Box 40, Folder 868)
  - Gardening, undated (Box 40, Folder 869)
  - Genealogy, undated (Box 40, Folder 870)
  - Greeting cards, undated (Box 40, Folder 871)
  - Harris family, 1944-1945, undated (Box 40, Folder 872)
  - Harris, Cornelia Robertson Burton
    - Vital records, 1882, 1904, undated (Box 40, Folder 873)
    - Will, 1950 (Box 40, Folder 874)
  - Harris, Frank Werner, 1960 (Box 40, Folder 875)
  - Harris, Herbert Burton, 1956-1978, undated (Box 40, Folder 876)
  - Harris, Herbert Kempe, 1956-1968 (Box 40, Folder 877)
  - Harris, Herbert Taylor
    - Agreement with Elizabeth M. Page, 1954 (Box 40, Folder 878)
    - Bills and receipts, 1954-1958, undated (Box 40, Folder 879)
    - Diaries, 1955, 1957 (Box 40, Folder 880)
    - Estate, 1960, undated (Box 40, Folder 881)
    - Finances, 1955-1957 (Box 40, Folder 882)
    - Florida information, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 883)
    - Herbert T. Harris Trust
      - Accounting, 1959-1968 (Box 41, Folder 884-890)
      - Correspondence, 1959-1968 (Box 41, Folder 891-894)
      - First National Bank of Casper, 1959 (Box 41, Folder 895)
      - Investment analysis, 1961-1969 (Box 41, Folder 896)
      - Trust agreement, 1959-1967 (Box 41, Folder 897)
    - Marriage license, 1906 (Box 41, Folder 898)
    - Obituary, 1960 (Box 41, Folder 899)
    - Papers, 1913-1954, undated (Box 41, Folder 900)
    - Poetry, 1912 (Box 41, Folder 901)
    - Prescriptions, 1954-1958, undated (Box 41, Folder 902)
    - Wills, 1950-1959 (Box 41, Folder 903)
  - Henry E. Huntington Library, 1939-1942 (Box 41, Folder 904)
  - Holt, Rinehart and Winston, Inc.: annual report, 1965 (Box 41, Folder 905)
  - Humorous, 1923, undated (Box 42, Folder 906)
  - Insurance, 1941-1966 (Box 42, Folder 907)
    - Annuity proposal, undated (Box 42, Folder 908)
    - Life insurance, 1925-1948 (Box 42, Folder 909)
  - Keeter, Clarence O., 1918-1920 (Box 42, Folder 910)
  - Kellogg, Theodora (Box 42, Folder 910)
    - The Making Of Italy
      - Correspondence, 1919 (Box 42, Folder 911)
      - Index, 1919 (Box 42, Folder 912)
      - Manuscript, 1919 (Box 42, Folder 913-914)
      - Notes, Circa 1919 (Box 42, Folder 915-916)
    - Miscellaneous, 1919, 1924, undated (Box 42, Folder 917)
    - Newspaper clippings, 1930-1947, undated (Box 42, Folder 918-920)
    - Papers, 1934-1947, undated (Box 42, Folder 921)
    - Photographs, 1908, 1917 (Box 42, Folder 922)
    - Poetry, 1921, undated (Box 42, Folder 923)
    - Printed works, 1939, undated (Box 42, Folder 924)
    - "Public Library Extension Work in the Prison", 1934 (Box 42, Folder 925)
    - Writings in her head, undated (Box 42, Folder 926)
  - Licenses and identification, 1931-1953, undated (Box 42, Folder 927)
  - Lists, 1945-1965, undated (Box 42, Folder 928)
  - Lyman family, 1949-1964, undated (Box 42, Folder 929)
  - Lyman, Elizabeth Dudley Schauffler, undated (Box 43, Folder 930)
  - Manchester, Vermont
    - Annual reports of Town of Manchester, 1941-1967 (Box 43, Folder 931-932)
    - Annual reports of Village of Manchester, 1943-1968 (Box 43, Folder 933)
    - Battenkill Co-Operative Locker, Inc., 1945-1954 (Box 43, Folder 934)
    - Brochures and other printed items, 1951-1968, undated (Box 43, Folder 935)
    - Burr and Burton Seminary, 1958, undated (Box 43, Folder 936)
    - First Congregational Church, 1942, 1967, undated (Box 43, Folder 937)
    - House construction, 1961 (Box 43, Folder 938)
    - House information, undated (Box 43, Folder 939)
    - House inventories, 1946-1968, undated (Box 43, Folder 940-941)